NABEEL ALI

(Please Contact directly for full CV) | nabeelali_@outlook.com | linkedin.com/in/nabeelshahanali | https://nabzali.github.io/my-site

PROFILE

An AWS-certified Software Engineer with 3-4 years of experience developing web applications. Driven by the ever-evolving landscape of technology and the opportunity to solve real-world problems. Aims to continue harnessing this passion to transform businesses and empower customers. Familiar with, and passionate about Generative A.I and Cloud Technologies

SKILLS

Technologies: React (JavaScript/TypeScript), AWS (Lambda, DynamoDb, S3, etc), NodeJs, C#, Git, Github, RESTful APIs, Unit Testing (Jest), Databases (SQL & NoSQL e.g. DynamoDb/SQL Server)

Practices: Agile, DevOps, Unit Testing, Consultancy, Feature-demoing, UX/UI development

Others: Terraform, Windows OS, Postman, Chrome Devtools, Generative A.I, CI/CD (Github Actions, Jenkins)

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer & Consultant | Reply

London, United Kingdom

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Drove the success of multiple easyJet plc projects, including "FAST" (Frontline Assistance Tool) an AI-powered React/AWS-based app used in 50+ airports to provide real-time updates streamlining operations and customer service
- Led key development decisions, including UI component design, RESTful API architecture, and optimising AWS service usage
- Acted as a hands-on technical consultant throughout, working directly with clients to gather requirements, present solutions, and align delivery with business goals

Junior Software Engineer | Mazepoint

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

London, United Kingdom

- Used Angular/.NET/SQL Server aid the development of Mazeinsight, a data-driven business enterprise solution
- Improved the internal DevOps process by using Jenkins and PowerShell scripting to reduce deployment time by 7 hours

Technology Rotation - University Placement Year | IBM

JULY 2019 - JULY 2020

Nottingham, United Kingdom

- Improved proficiency in Software Engineering principles (Agile, Scrum) and technologies (C# and OOP, VS2019, Git) whilst writing automated tests for a windows desktop application, thus successfully detecting bugs within the software
- Student hackathon winning team collaboratively designed and proposed an idea for an "expiry date prediction system"

Volunteer Youth Worker | National Citizen Service (NCS)

JULY 2015 - OCTOBER 2015

United Kingdom

- Financially managed a fundraising campaign, ensuring that expenses fell within a given budget
- Delivered a public speech on education to approximately 80 attendees, displaying strong oral communication as a result
- Developed teambuilding through the participation of collaborative, demanding outdoor activities such as boat racing

EDUCATION

BSc Hons Computer Science with Year in Industry (2:1) | University of Nottingham

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2021

- Nottingham, United Kingdom
- Modules included: Advanced Algorithms & Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Databases & Interfaces
- Projects included: Unity C# 3D open world island survival game and data-driven CRUD app on artists/albums/songs
- Societies/Activities: Open Day Ambassador, Charity Week, and Jumpers for goalposts (football)

Beal High School

SEPTEMBER 2010 - JUNE 2017

Redbridge, Greater London, United Kingdom

• A Level: Mathematics (A), Economics (A) and Computer Science (A)

ACHIEVEMENTS AND PROJECTS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

JANUARY 2024

• IBM Undergrad Placement Hackathon winner + Python for Data Science certification

NOVEMBER 2019

• UKMT Maths Challenge – GOLD Award

APRIL 2015

Trialist at Chelsea FC MAY 2010

INTERESTS/OTHER

Interests: 7-a-side football, kickboxing, travelling, culture & languages, current affairs, fundraising, reading